Guide to the Roland F. Pease Papers, 1831-2005 (bulk 1940-2000)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Roland F. Pease Papers
1831-2005
1940-2000
Pease, Roland
14.6 cubic feet (17 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to the life and work of author and art collector, Roland F. Pease (1921-2012). Of particular interest is material related to his involvement with the Tibor de Nagy Gallery in New York City, as well as his work for several religious and fraternal organizations, such as the Society of Mayflower Descendants, the New England Society, and St. James' Church.
Biographical Note
Roland F. Pease (1921-2012) was an American writer, editor, and art collector. He was born in Boston, MA, on 11 December 1921 to Roland F. Pease and Mary (Hallett) Pease. He was the father of Rosland F. Pease, Jr., and publisher Deborah Saltonstall Pease.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, writings, photographs and other material relating to Pease's work and family life as well as his civic and religious affiliations and connections to the art world. Of particular interest are materials relating to his friendship with Tibor de Nagy and his involvement with the Tibor de Nagy Gallery in New York City. Also of note is a large cache of genealogical material relating to the Pease, Folsom, and Saltonstall families. The collection also includes material relating to Pease's involvement with several civic and religious organizations, including the Society of Mayflower Descendants, the New England Society, and St. James' Church in New York City.
Access
Contains some restricted material. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Names:
Pease, Deborah; Pease Family; Folsom Family; Saltonstall Family
Organizations:
Tibor de Nagy Gallery; Society of Mayflower Descendants; New England Society; St. James' Church (New York, N.Y.)
VCL Categories:
Art and Artists; Family; Journalism
Encoding Information
Encoded by Jennifer Palmentiero, March 2006. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, July 2025.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Roland F. Pease in several accessions, 1999-2005.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 8 series and arranged chronologically within each of those series.
Series List
- Series I. Biography, 1942-2002
- Series II. Education, 1934-2005
- Series III. Journals, 1932-2002
- Series IV. Personal Correspondence, 1942-2003
- Series V. Organizations and Institutions, 1952-2003
- Series VI. Writings, 1940-1999
- Series VII. Photographs, 1831-2003
- Series VIII. Ephemera, 1938-2000
Container List
- SERIES I. Biography, 1942-2002
  - General, 1942-2002 (Folder 1.1)
  - Chronicles of the Pease Family scrapbook, 1942-1972 (Box 14)
  - Military Records, 1942-1945 (Folder 1.2)
  - Letters of Recommendation for Apartment on E. 72nd St., 1984 (Folder 1.3)
  - Fairfield Porter Portrait, circa 1984-1997 (Folder 1.4)
  - Film, Art and Theatre Clippings, 2000-2001 (Folder 1.5)
  - Travels — Spain, 1993 (Folder 1.6)
  - Travels — London, 1993 (Folder 1.7)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family Documents, 1856-1974 (Folder 1.8)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Genealogy, circa 1911-1999 (Folder 1.9)
  - Pease Genealogy by the American Historical Company, 1956 (Folder 9.22)
  - Pease and Saltonstall Genealogical Charts, undated (Box 16)
  - Saltonstall Genealogy, circa 1956-1999 (Folder 1.10)
  - Saltonstall Family Portraits, 1962, 1999 (Folder 1.11)
  - RFP's Apartment Tour [VHS Tape], 1997 (Folder 8.25)
  - Interview with RFP by Marianne Buchenhorner re: Tibor de Nagy, 2002; (VHS Tape) (Folder 8.26)
- SERIES II. Education, 1934-2005
  - Newton Public Schools
    - General, 1934-1943 (Folder 1.12)
    - High School Diploma, 1939 (Folder 1.13)
    - Reunions, 1964, 1979 (Folder 1.14)
    - Theater Papers, 1939 (Folder 1.15)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, circa 1935-1939 (Folder 1.16)
  - Kimball Union Academy
    - General, 1939-2001 (Folder 1.17)
    - Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Dartmouth College
    - General, 1943 (Folder 1.18)
    - Notebooks, circa 1940-1944 (Folder 1.19)
  - Columbia University
    - General, 1943-1946 (Folder 1.20)
    - General, 1989 (Folder 9.12)
    - General, 2001, 2005 (Folder 1.20)
    - Notebooks, circa 1946-1948 (Folder 1.21)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Papers, circa 1946-1947 (Folder 1.22)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Boston University — Intercession Notebooks and Papers, 1947 (Folder 1.23)
    - Unidentified Notebooks, circa 1950s (Folder 1.24)
    - Institute of Theology, Cathedral of Saint John the Divine, circa 1974-1975 (Folder 9.9)
    - Institute of Theology, Cathedral of Saint John the Divine, circa 1974-1976 (Folder 9.10)
    - Yeats International Summer School, 1980 (Folder 9.11)
- SERIES III. Journals, 1932-2002
  - Day calendar, 1932 (Box 11)
  - Five year diary, 1932 (Box 11)
  - Day book, 1945 Jan (Box 11)
  - Journal I, 1964 Oct-1965 Jan (Box 2)
  - Journal II, 1965 Jan-Feb (Box 2)
  - Journal III, 1965 Mar-Apr (Box 2)
  - Journal IV, 1965 Apr-May (Box 2)
  - Journal V, 1965 May-Jun (Box 2)
  - Journal VI, 1965 Jun-Jul (Box 2)
  - Journal VII, 1965 Jul-Aug (Box 2)
  - Journal VIII, 1965 Aug-Sep (Box 2)
  - Journal IX, 1965 Sep (Box 2)
  - Journal X, 1965 Sep (Box 2)
  - Journal XI, 1965 Sep-Oct (Box 2)
  - Journal XII, 1966 Jul-Aug (Box 2)
  - Journal XIII, 1966 Aug (Box 2)
  - Journal XIV, 1966 Sep-Oct (Box 2)
  - Journal XV, 1966 Oct-Nov (Box 2)
  - Journal XVI, 1966 Nov-Dec (Box 2)
  - Journal XVII, 1966 Dec (Box 2)
  - Dear Olivia — Greece, 1966 (Folder 2.1)
  - Ten Days in London, 1967 Dec-1968 Jan (Box 2)
  - Europe, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Spain and France, 1969 Jul (Box 11)
  - Europe, 1970 Jun-Jul (Folder 9.1)
  - England, 1971 Jul (Folder 2.2)
  - Easthampton Long Island, 1973 Aug-Sep (Folder 2.3)
  - New England, 1974 Aug (Folder 9.2)
  - England, Austria, Italy, 1975 Summer (Folder 9.3)
  - Mt. Cavalry Retreat House, Santa Barbara, CA, 1975 Dec (Folder 9.4)
  - England and the Middle East, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Nassau, Bahamas, 1976-1977 (Folder 2.4)
  - Delta Queen Cruise on the Mississippi, 1977 (Folder 2.5)
  - Journal of a Sojourn in London, England, 1977 Jun-Jul (Box 12)
  - Journal of a Cruise (a months long voyage) on the Norwegian ship the Royal Viking Sky, 1977 Jul-Aug (Box 11)
  - A Journal dedicated to dear Elsa Ives whom I visited for a week in Antigua, 1978 Feb (Box 11)
  - Britain and Bermuda, 1978 Jun (Folder 9.5)
  - RFP Summer Travels, Vol 1, 1979 (Box 11)
  - RFP Summer Travels, Vol 2, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Switzerland, Germany and Austria, 1979 Dec-1980 Jan (Folder 9.6)
  - Bermuda, Ireland, England and Colorado, 1980 Summer (Folder 2.6)
  - Mexico, 1980 Dec-1981 Jan (Folder 2.7)
  - Bermuda, England and France, 1981 (Box 12)
  - France, 1981 Aug (Box 12)
  - Bermuda and Europe, 1982 Summer (Folder 2.8)
  - New York, New England and Europe, 1983 Summer (Folder 2.9)
  - England, Austria, France and Massachusetts, 1984 Jul-Sep (Folder 2.10)
  - Europe, New York and New England, 1986 Jul-Sep (Folder 2.11)
  - Bermuda, England and Austria, 1987 Jun-Sep (Folder 2.12)
  - England Austria, New England, 1988 (Box 12)
  - England Austria, New York, 1989 (Box 12)
  - RFP on Stage in London, 1994 May (Folder 2.13)
  - Albion — London, 1996 Jun (Folder 2.14)
  - Paris, London and Dublin, 1997 (Folder 2.15)
  - England and Scotland, 1998 (Folder 2.16)
  - London, 1977 Dec-1998 Jan (Folder 2.17)
  - Archives [Vassar College], 1999 Jun-Aug (Folder 9.7)
  - Archives Journal, 2000 Apr-Sep (Folder 2.18)
  - Dublin and London, 2000 Oct (Folder 2.19)
  - RFP's Summer, 2001 Aug (Folder 2.20)
  - Journal, 2002 Jan (Folder 2.21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-2002 (Folder 9.8)
- SERIES IV. Personal Correspondence, 1942-2003
  - Adams, Margaret [Mrs. Basil], 1967-1973 (Folder 1.25)
  - Carlisle, Louise Emerson, 1956-1957 (Folder 1.26)
  - Castoro, Rosemarie, 1994-1999 (Folder 1.27)
  - Cramworth Family and Friends, 1967-1981 (Folder 1.28)
  - Cushman, Carole, circa 1990-1991 (Folder 1.29)
  - de Nagy, Tibor — General, 1986-1993 (Folder 1.30)
  - de Nagy, Tibor — Correspondence re Illness and Death, 1993-1994 (Folder 1.31)
  - de Nagy, Tibor — Sympathy Letters upon his Death, 1993-1994 (Folder 1.32)
  - Farah, Adelaide P., 1994-2002, n.d. (Folder 1.33)
  - [To] Foster, Grace [Mrs. Brent] from RFP, 1942-1943 (Folder 1.34)
  - [To] Foster, Grace [Mrs. Brent] from RFP, 1944-1945 (Folder 1.35)
  - [To] Foster, Grace [Mrs. Brent] from Polly Pease, 1942 (Folder 1.36)
  - Gordon, Lilly [Sister of Tibor de Nagy], 1982-1990 (Folder 9.13)
  - Hallett, Isabel E., 1957 (Folder 1.37)
  - Kellogg, Robert, 1957 (Folder 1.38)
  - Knox, Timothy and Elizabeth, 1997-2003 (Folder 1.41)
  - L'Engle, Madeleine, 1975 (Folder 1.39)
  - Lewis, Muriel Gordon Saltonstall, circa 1957-1989 (Folder 1.40)
  - Pease, Deborah, 1974-1998 (Folder 3.1)
  - Pease, Deborah, 2000-2002, undated (Folder 3.2)
  - Pease, Deborah — "Fan Mail" for "Another Ghost, ", 1999 (Folder 3.3)
  - Pease, Polly Saltonstall, 1942 May-Aug (Folder 3.4)
  - Pease, Polly Saltonstall, 1942 Aug 19-27 (Folder 3.5)
  - Pease, Polly Saltonstall, 1942 Aug-Oct (Folder 3.6)
  - Pease, Polly Saltonstall, 1942-1946 (Folder 3.7)
  - [To] Pease, Polly Saltonstall from RFP, 1945 (Folder 3.8)
  - Pease, Roland F. Jr. [Ron], 1973-2002 (Folder 3.9)
  - Perry, Marilyn and John, 1944-1945 (Folder 3.10)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance and Mary, 1990-1998 (Folder 9.15)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1973-1977 (Folder 3.11)
  - Saltonstall, Mary and Richard, circa 1942-1982 (Folder 3.12)
  - Saltonstall, William L., circa 1980-2000 (Folder 3.13)
  - Saltonstalls — Miscellaneous, circa 1970-2000 (Folder 3.14)
  - Vietor, Anna Glenn, circa 1995-2000 (Folder 3.15)
  - Willis, Sally Saltonstall and Dudley H., circa 1980-2001 (Folder 3.16)
  - English Friends, 1948-1956 (Folder 3.17)
  - Texas Family, 1971 (Folder 3.18)
  - Congratulatory Letters on RFP's Investment in the Order of the Hospital of St. John, 1974 (Folder 3.19)
  - Sympathy Letters on the Death of Mary Hallett Pease [RFP'S Mother], 1948 (Folder 3.20)
  - Sympathy Letters on the Death of Roland F. Pease, Sr. [RFP'S Father], 1969 (Folder 3.21)
  - Correspondence Associated with 1971 trip to England (Folder 9.14)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1948-2000 (Folder 3.22)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1995-2002 (Folder 3.23)
- SERIES V. Organizations and Institutions, 1952-2003
  - Church Club of New York, 1996-2001 (Folder 3.24)
  - Davis Museum and Cultural Center, 1996-1998 (Folder 3.25)
  - Holy Cross Monastery, circa 1974-1988 (Folder 3.26)
  - House of the Redeemer — General, 1971-1986 (Folder 3.27)
  - House of the Redeemer — Christmas Concert [dedicated to Polly S. Pease], 1974 (Folder 3.28)
  - House of the Redeemer — Christmas Concert, 1975-1976 (Folder 3.29)
  - House of the Redeemer — Christmas Concert, 1977-1978 (Folder 3.30)
  - Metropolitan Opera Club, 1988-1993, 2000 (Folder 3.31)
  - New England Society — Board Meeting Minutes, 1984-2000 (Folder 4.1)
  - New England Society — Bulletins, 1977-2000 (Folder 4.2)
  - New England Society — Correspondence and Notes, 1976-1980 (Folder 4.3)
  - New England Society — Correspondence and Notes, 1981-2001 (Folder 4.4)
  - Order of the Hospital of St. John, 1974-2001 (Folder 4.5)
  - Pilgrim of John Howland Society, 1967-1994 (Folder 9.16)
  - Royal Academy of the Arts, 1996 (Folder 4.6)
  - St. James Church, 1972-1985 (Folder 4.7)
  - St. James Church, 1986-1990 (Folder 4.8)
  - St. James Church, 1992-1997 (Folder 4.9)
  - St. James Church, 1998-2001 (Folder 4.10)
  - St. James Church — re Tom Faulkner, 1997 (Folder 4.11)
  - St. James Church — "Ministry Honouring Mr. Roland Pease, ", 1999; (Audio cassette tape) (Box 13)
  - Sherborn, MA Library, Town, etc., 1983-1999 (Folder 4.12)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1965-1985 (Folder 4.13)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1986-1990 (Folder 4.14)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1991-1992 (Folder 4.15)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1993-1994 (Folder 4.16)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1995-1997 (Folder 4.17)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1998-2003, n.d. (Folder 4.18)
  - Sons of the Revolution, 1968-1969 (Folder 4.19)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — General, 1994-2002 (Folder 5.1)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Allen Ginsberg Exhibit, 1997 (Folder 5.2)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Pease Collection Exhibit — "Art and Friendship, ", 1997 (Folder 5.3)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Pease Collection Exhibit — "Art and Friendship" — Congratulations and Thanks, 1997 (Folder 5.4)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Miscellaneous Clippings, circa 1990-2001 (Folder 5.5)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Marionette Company, 1950 (Folder 9.17)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery — Oversized Items, circa 1985-1990 (Folder 9.18)
  - Union Club, 1976-1986 (Folder 5.6)
  - United Press, 1952-1955 (Folder 5.7)
  - Vassar College — General, 1998-2002 (Folder 5.8)
  - Vassar College — RFP Art Collection, 1997-1998 (Folder 5.9)
  - [RESTRICTED] Vassar College — RFP Art Collection — Appraisals, 1989, 1997-1998 (Folder 7.22)
  - Yale University Library, 1999-2001 (Folder 5.10)
  - [RESTRICTED] Yale University Library — Appraisals, 1998 (Folder 7.23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-2003, n.d. (Folder 5.11)
- SERIES VI. Writings, 1940-1999
  - Letters from Publishers, Editors and Literary Agents, 1949-1987 (Folder 5.12)
  - Dartmouth College Short Stories and Essays, folder 1 of 2, 1940-1941 (Folder 5.13)
  - Dartmouth College Short Stories and Essays, folder 2 of 2, 1940-1941 (Folder 5.14)
  - Short Stories for Mabel Louise Robinson, Columbia, University, 1942-1943 (Folder 5.15)
  - Short Stories for Helen Hull, Columbia University, 1946 (Folder 5.16)
  - Essays and Short Stories, 1947-1953 (Folder 5.17)
  - The Townsman [Wellesley MA newspaper] scrapbook, 1948-1949 (Box 15)
  - There'll Always be a New England, The Kiwanis Magazine, 1951 (Folder 5.18)
  - Having a Wonderful Time, Boston Herald, 1951 (Folder 5.19)
  - New England Newsletter articles, 1951-1952 (Folder 5.20)
  - United Press Articles, 1952-1955 (Folder 9.19)
  - United Press Articles, 1952-1955 (Folder 9.20)
  - United Press Notebook, 1952-1954 (Folder 9.21)
  - Gravel, 1956 (Folder 5.21)
  - Short Stories, 1955-1956 (Folder 5.22)
  - Native Idylls — First Drafts, folder 1 of 2, 1955-1956 (Folder 5.23)
  - Native Idylls — First Drafts, folder 2 of 2, 1955-1956 (Folder 5.24)
  - Native Idylls — Marked Draft, circa 1957 (Folder 5.25)
  - Native Idylls — "Ribbon Copy,", circa 1957 (Folder 5.26)
  - Native Idylls — Clean Copy, pp. 1-120, circa 1957 (Folder 5.27)
  - Native Idylls — Clean Copy, pp. 201-411, circa 1957 (Folder 6.1)
  - Sweet Nothing — Original Manuscript, pp. 1-149, circa 1956 (Folder 6.2)
  - Sweet Nothing — Original Manuscript, pp. 150-385, circa 1956 (Folder 6.3)
  - Sweet Nothing — Edited Draft, pp. 1-178, circa 1956 (Folder 6.4)
  - Sweet Nothing — Edited Draft, pp. 179-363, circa 1956 (Folder 6.5)
  - Sweet Nothing — Final Typescript, Volume 1, 1957 (Folder 6.6)
  - Sweet Nothing — Final Typescript, Volume 2, 1957 (Folder 6.7)
  - Sweet Nothing — Reviews and Correspondence, 1957-1996 (Folder 6.8)
  - Sweet Nothing — Scrapbook, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Wildwood — Clean Copy, pp. 1-231, circa 1957 (Folder 6.9)
  - Wildwood — Clean Copy, pp. 232-440, circa 1957 (Folder 6.10)
  - Wildwood — Incomplete Draft, circa 1957 (Folder 6.11)
  - Wildwood — Marked Draft, pp. 1-165, circa 1957 (Folder 6.12)
  - Wildwood — Marked Draft, pp. 166-335, circa 1957 (Folder 6.13)
  - A Cold Caress — Marked Draft, pp. 1-131, circa 1957 (Folder 6.14)
  - A Cold Caress — Marked Draft, pp. 132-261, circa 1957 (Folder 6.15)
  - A Cold Caress — Marked Draft, pp. 262-427, circa 1957 (Folder 6.16)
  - A Cold Caress — Notes and Corrections, circa 1957 (Folder 6.17)
  - A Cold Caress — Clean Copy, pp 1-217, circa 1957 (Folder 6.18)
  - A Cold Caress — Clean Copy, pp 218-437, circa 1957 (Folder 7.1)
  - My Shadow, circa 1950s (Folder 7.2)
  - Charity — Clean Typescript, pp. 1-123, circa 1950s (Folder 7.3)
  - Charity — Clean Typescript, pp. 124-297, circa 1950s (Folder 7.4)
  - Charity — Handwritten Draft, circa 1950s (Folder 7.5)
  - Pictures on Exhibit work, 1960-1961 (Folder 7.6)
  - Pictures on Exhibit work, 1961-1962 (Folder 7.7)
  - Art International articles, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Art Voices [RFP executive editor], 1962-1966 (Box 10)
  - Art USA Now article on Larry Rivers, 1962 (Folder 7.21)
  - Notes on a Course in Publishing and Editing, 1963 (Folder 7.8)
  - Metro articles, circa 1963-1965 (Box 10)
  - Holy Cross News layout, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Holy Cross Magazine [Editorial work?], 1961-1965 (Box 10)
  - The Benefactress [dramatization of Sweet Nothing], circa 1960s (Folder 7.9)
  - Undercurrents work, 1975 (Folder 7.10)
  - Elsewhere — Typescript, pp 1-167, 1988 (Folder 7.11)
  - Elsewhere — Typescript, pp 168-343, 1988 (Folder 7.12)
  - Elsewhere — Notes and Corrections, circa 1988, 1999 (Folder 7.13)
  - Elsewhere — Associated Material, 1988 (Folder 7.14)
  - Travels with Myself, 1993 (Folder 7.15)
  - "Meditations on Poetrics” ", 1993-1994 (Folder 7.16)
  - Polly Saltonstall's Charlescote Farm..., ", 1995 (Folder 7.17)
  - Journal, pp. 1-300, undated (Folder 7.18)
  - Journal, pp. 301-600, undated (Folder 7.19)
  - Journal, pp. 601-884, undated (Folder 7.20)
- SERIES VII. Photographs, 1831-2003
  - RFP Portraits, circa 1940, 1963 (Box 17)
  - RFP Portraits and Snapshots, 1939-circa 2000 (Folder 8.1)
  - Polly Saltonstall Pease, circa 1920-1946 (Folder 8.2)
  - Roland Polly Pease Wedding Album, 1942 (Folder 8.3)
  - RFP Family, circa 1940-1950 (Folder 8.4)
  - RFP Family Album [includes RFP's tour in Europe], 1942-1945 (Box 10)
  - Deborah Saltonstall Pease, circa 1942-1975 (Folder 8.5)
  - Roland F. Pease, Jr. (Ron) and Family, circa 1989-2000 (Folder 8.6)
  - Folsom - Pease Family Album, circa 1910-1921 (Box 10)
  - Folsom - Pease Family Album, circa 1920-1930 (Box 10)
  - Folsom - Pease Family Album, 1930-1942 (Box 10)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, circa 1860-1910 (Folder 8.7)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, circa 1860-1910 (Folder 8.8)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, circa 1860-1910 (Folder 8.9)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, circa 1860-1910 (Folder 8.10)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family - Oversize, circa 1860-1910 (Box 17)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, 1969 (Folder 8.11)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett Family, circa 1920-1995 (Folder 8.12)
  - Saltonstall Family, circa 1870-2000 (Folder 8.13)
  - Saltonstall Family - Mrs. Gorham Brooks, 1831 (Box 17)
  - Pease/Folsom/Hallett [and Saltonstall ?] Family tin types and daguerreotypes, circa 1850-1900 (Box 13)
  - RFP's 80th Birthday Party, 2001 (Folder 8.14)
  - RFP at Studio of Any Warhol, circa 1950s (Box 10)
  - Tibor de Nagy and RFP, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Tibor de Nagy and Lilly Gordon, circa 1960-1989 (Box 17)
  - Adelaide P. Farah, circa 1990-2003 (Folder 8.15)
  - Elsa Ives, circa 1980-1990 (Folder 8.16)
  - Royal Academy Trust [RFP with Prince Charles], 1996 (Folder 8.17)
  - St. James Church, 1997-1998 (Folder 8.18)
  - Tibor de Nagy Gallery, 2000 (Folder 8.19)
  - House of the Redeemer, 1974 (Folder 8.20)
  - New England Society, 1988-1998 (Folder 8.21)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants, 1981-2000 (Folder 8.22)
  - Vassar College, circa 1998-2000 (Folder 8.23)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1970-2000 (Folder 8.24)
- SERIES VIII. Ephemera, 1938-2000
  - Postcards, circa 1940-2000 (Folder 8.27)
  - Tickets and Stubs, 1938-1939 (Folder 8.28)
  - Robert Goodnough "Dinosaurs Visit the Stamford Museum,", undated; (VHS tape) (Box 10)
  - Pins and Ribbons, circa 1940-2000 (Box 13)